Finding Aid for the Frederick Taylor Wolf Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Frederick Taylor Wolf Papers
Inclusive: 1911-1994; Bulk: 1930s, 1960s
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0522
15 linear_feet
Scope and Content Note
The Frederick Taylor Wolf Papers include correspondence, botanic publications, writings, and research materials, conference and travel materials, teaching and lecture materials, and notes from when Professor Wolf was a student at Harvard University. The 12 cubic foot collection contains materials ranging from 1911 through 1994, with two major periods of collection in the 1930’s and 1960’s. Major topics of interest include career correspondence from 1935-1992, reprints of over 135 publications on mycology and microbiology, and Professor Wolf’s teaching materials.
- Correspondence
  - 1946-1947 (Box 1)
  - 1947-1948 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1947-1948 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1949-1950 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1949-1950 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1950-1951 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1950-1951 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1951-1952 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1951-1952 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1952-1953 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1952-1953 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1953-1954 (1 of 3) (Box 1)
  - 1953-1954 (2 of 3) (Box 1)
  - 1953-1954 (3 of 3) (Box 1)
  - 1954-1955 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1954-1955 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1955-1956 (1 of 3) (Box 1)
  - 1955-1956 (2 of 3) (Box 1)
  - 1955-1956 (3 of 3) (Box 1)
  - 1956-1957 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1956-1957 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1957-1958 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1957-1958 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - 1958-1959 (1 of 2) (Box 2)
  - 1958-1959 (2 of 2) (Box 2)
  - 1959-1960 (1 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1959-1960 (2 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1959-1960 (3 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1960-1961 (1 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1960-1961 (2 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1960-1961 (3 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1961-1962 (1 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1961-1962 (2 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1961-1962 (3 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1962-1963 (1 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1962-1963 (2 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1962-1963 (3 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1963-1964 (1 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1963-1964 (2 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1963-1964 (3 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1964-1965 (1 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1964-1965 (2 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1964-1965 (3 of 3) (Box 2)
  - 1965-1966 (1 of 2) (Box 2)
  - 1965-1966 (2 of 2) (Box 2)
  - 1966-1967 (1 of 2) (Box 2)
  - 1966-1967 (2 of 2) (Box 2)
  - 1967-1968 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1967-1968 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1968-1969 (1 of 3) (Box 3)
  - 1968-1969 (2 of 3) (Box 3)
  - 1968-1969 (3 of 3) (Box 3)
  - 1969-1970 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1969-1970 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1970-1971 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1970-1971 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1971-1972 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1971-1972 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - 1973-1974 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1973-1974 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1974-1975 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1974-1975 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1975-1976 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1975-1976 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - 1978-1979 (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - 1978-1979 (2 of 2) (Box 4)
  - 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - 1980-1981 (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - 1980-1981 (2 of 2) (Box 4)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 4)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 4)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - 1935-1938 Weston (Box 4)
  - 1935-1939 (Box 4)
  - 1938-1939 (N.R.C. Fellowship) (Box 4)
  - 1939 (Box 4)
  - 1940 (Box 4)
  - 1941 (Box 4)
  - 1941-1942 (Box 4)
  - 1944, 1945 (Box 4)
  - 1946 (Box 4)
- Subject Files (Mostly Publications), Unlabeled folder with Syllabus, Bibiography and Chemisty 15 Thesis
  - The Pathology of Tobacco Black Shank From Phytopathology, July 1933, Vol XXIII, No 7 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - A Nutritional Study of Achlya Bisexuals and Saprolegnia Ferax from American Journal Of Botany Vol. 24, No 3, March 1937 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Some Sporangial Variations in Saprolegnia Ferax from Mycologia Vol XXIX, No 2, March 1937 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Achlya Flagellata as a Fish Parasite from Jour. Mitchell Scientific Soc. Vol 33, No 2, Dec 1937 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Two New Saprolegniaceous Fungi from Amer. Jour. Of Botany Vol 25, No 6, June 1938 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cytological Observations on Gametogenesis and Fertilization in Achlya Flagellata from Mycologia Vol XXX, No 4, July 1938 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Snail Polygrya Thyroidus as a Mycophagist from Bul. Torrey Botanical Club 66, Jan 1939 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - A Study of Botryosphaeria Ribis on Willow from Mycologia Vol XXXI, No 2, March 1939 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - A Study of Some Aquatic Phycomycetes Isolated from Mexican Soils from Mycologia Vol XXXI, No 4, July 1939 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Macrosporogenesis and the Development of the Embryo Sac in Yucca Aloifolia from Bul. Torrey Botanical Club Vol 67 No 9, Dec 1940 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - The Genus Allomyces in Cuba from Lloydia Vol 3, Dec 1940 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Development of the Embryo Sac in Agave Virginica from Bul. Torrey Botanical Club Vol 68 No 4, April 1941 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - A Contribution to the Life History and Geographic Distribution of the Genus Allomyces from Mycologia Vol XXXIII, No 2, March 1941 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - A New Species of Achlya from Costa Rica from Mycologia Vol XXXIII, No 3, May 1941 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - An Addition to the Fungus Flora of Barro Colorado Island From Transactions of the British Mycological Society Vol XXV, Part II, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Aquatic Phycomycetes from the Everglades Region of Florida from Llyodia Vol4, Dec 1941 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - The Microbiology of the Upper Air from Bul Torrey Botanical Club Vol 70 No 1, Jan 1943 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - The Effects of Certain Sugars and Amino Acids Upon the Respiration of Allomyces from Mycologia Vol XXXV No 2, Mar 1943 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Treatment of External Otitis from Archives of Otolaryngology Jan 1945 Vol 41 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 21-25 The Action of Sulfonamides on Certain Fungi Pathogenic to Man Project Report for 27th AAF Base Unit AF School of Aviation Medicine Randolph Field, Texas, Jan 16, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - The Action of Sulfonamides on Certain Fungi Pathogenic to Man from Mycologia Vol XXXVIII No 2, Mar 1946 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - The Action of Cyanie upon the Respiration of the aquatic fungus, Allomyces from Journal of Cell. And Comp. Physiolgoy Vol 28 No 3, December 1946 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - The Oxidation of Carbohydrates by a surface Strain of Penicillium Notatum from Archives of Biochemistry Vol 13 No 1, Apr 1947 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Relation of Various Fungi to Otomycosis from Archives of Otolaryngology Vol 46, Sep 1947 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - The Action of Sulfonamides and Antibiotic Agents on the Pathogenic Fungi From Biology of Pathogenic Fungi Vol 6, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - The Amino Acid Metabolism of Penicillium Chrysogenum Q-176 From Archives of Biochemisty Vol 16 No 1, Jan 1948 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - The Origin of Tobaccos of the Oriental Type From Bul Torrey Botanical Club Vol 75 No1, Jan 1948 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - A Toxic Metabolic Product of Fusarium Oxysporm Var. Nicotianae in Relation to the Wilting of Tobacco Plants from Phytopathology Vol XXXVIII No 4, Apr 1948 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - The Action of Sulfonamides on Certain Fungi Pathogenic to Man from Mycologia Vol XXXVIII No 2, Mar 1946 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Amino Acids in the Biosynthesis of Penicillin from Mycologia Vol XLI No 4, Jul 1949 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Morphological Effects of Thymol and Related Compounds Upon the Germination of Fungus Spores from Bul Torrey Botanical Club Vol 77, No 2, March 1950 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - The Nutrition of Monosporium Apiospermum from Mycologia Vol XLII No 2, March 1950 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Chemical Agents for the Control of Molds on Meats from Mycologia Vol XLII, No3, May 1950 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Inhibition of Pathongenic fungi in vitro ny p-Hydroxy Methyl Benzoate from Separatum Vol V No1, March 1950 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Pathology of Camellia Leaves Infected by Exobasidium Camelliae Var. Gracilis Shirai from Phytopathology Vol 42, no 3, March 1952 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - The Cultivation of Two Species of Entomophthora on Synthetic Media from Bul. Torrey Botanical Club Vol 78 no3, May 1951 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - The Production of Indole Acetic Aid by Ustilago Zeae, and its possible Significance in Tumor Formation from National Academy of Sciences Vol 38 No2, February 1952 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - The Effects of Certain Purines and Pyrimidines upon the Production of Riboflavin by Eremothecium Ashbyii from Journal of Baceriology Vol 63, no 2, February 1952 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Pathology of Camellia Leaves Infected by Exobasidium Camelliae Var. Gracilis Shirai from Phytopathology Vol 42, no 3, March 1952 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Some Fungi from Central Tennessee from Reelfoot Lake Biological Station Vol 17 1953 and Journal Tennessee Academy of Science Vol 28 No1, January 1953 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - The Utilization of Carbon and Nitrogen Compounds by Ustilago Zeae from Mycologia Vol XLV No 4, July 1953 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - The Utilization of Nucleic Acid Derivatives by Neurospora from Mycologia Vol XLV No 6, November 1953 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - The Utilization of Carbon and Nitrogen Compounds By Phytophthora Parasitica Dastur Var. Nicotianae (Breda De Haan) Tucker from Journal Mitchell Scientific Society Vol 70, No 2, December 1954 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - The Mechanism of Action of the Fungicide, 2-Heptadecyl-2-imidazoline from Journal of General Microbiology Vol 12, No 3, June 1955 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - The Chemical Composition of Leaves of Diseased Tobacco: Ring Spot, Bacterial Wilt and Fusarium Wilt From Phytopathology Vol 45 No 9, September 1955 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - The Chlorophyll Content of Certain Flue-Cured and Turkish Tobacco Varieties From Agronomy Journal Vol 47 No 8, August 1955 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - The Chlorophyll Content of Certain Flue-Cured and Turkish Tobacco Varieties From Biochimie (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Toxin Production by the Oak Wilt Fungus, Endoconidiophia Fagacearum from American Journal of Botany Vol 42, No 8, October 1955 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - The Production of Indole Acetic Acid by the Cedar Apple Rust Fungus, and Its Identification by Paper Chromatography from Phytopathologische Zeitschrift Band 26, Heft 2, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Absorption Spectra of the Anthocyanin Pigment of Red Cabbage: a Natural Wide-Range pH Indicator from Physiologia Plantarum Vol 9, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Changes in Chlorophylls A ad B in Autumn Leaves from American Journal of Botany Vol 43 No 9, November 1956 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Chemical Nature of the Fluorescent Pigment Produced in Microsporum Infected Hair from Nature Vol 180, October 1957 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - The Fluorescent Pigment of Aspergillus Repens from Physiologia Plantarum Vol 10 1957 Comparative Chlorophyll Content of the Two Generations of Bryophytes from Nature Vol 181, February 1958 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Chlorophylls A and B in the Pteridophytes Bul. Torrey Botanical Club Vol 85 No 1, January 1958 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - The Separation of Chloroplast Pigments by Unidimensional Ascending Paper Chromatography from Bul. Torrey Botanical Club Vol 85 No 2, March 1958 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Fluorescent Pigment of Microsporum from Nature Vol 182, August 1958 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Peronospora Parasitica on Leavenworthia from Journal Tennessee Academy of Science Vol 34 No 1, January 1959 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - The Chlorophyll Content of Tea from Bul Torrey Botanical Club Vol 86 No 3 May 1959 Chemical Nature of the Photorecptor Pigment Inducing Fruit of Plasmodia of Physarum Polycephalum from Photoperiodism and Related Phenomena in Plants and Animals (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - The Production of Indole Acetic Acid by Taphrina deformans and Dibotryon Morbosum from Physiologia Palntarum Vol 12 1959 The Separation of Chloroplast Pigments by Countercurrent Distribution from (Unknown) (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Chlorophyll Content of Gibberellin-Treated Wheat Seedlings from Nature Vol 186 April 1960 (1 of 2)nfluence of Amino Triazole on the Chloroplast Pigments of Wheat Seedlings from Nature Vol 188, October 1960 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Spectral Studies in Chrysogenin, a Pigment Produced by Penicillium Chrysogenum from Physiologia Plantarum Vol 13, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Pteridine Pigments in Microorganisms and Higher Plant from Comparative Biochemistry of Photoreactive Systems, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - The Utilization of Nucleic Acid Derivatives by Penicillium Chrysogenum from Bul Torrey Botanical Club Vol 88 No 1, January 1961 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Growth Inhibition of Chlorella Induced by 3 -Amino-1, 2, 4- Triazole, and its Reversal by Purines from Nature Vol 193 No 4818, March 1962 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Fatty Acids of Spinach Chloroplasts from Plant Physiology Vol 37 No 1, January 1962 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Studies on Monilia Sitophila from Indonesia from Bul Torrey Botanical Club Vol 88 No 6, November 1961 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Effects of Light and Darkness on Biosynthesis of Carotenoid Pigments in Wheat Seedlings Plant Physiology Vol.38 No 6, November 1963 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - The Pigments of Microsporum Cookei from Journal of Investigative Dermatology Vol 39 No 3, September 1962 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Nutrition of Three Species of Microsporum from Separatum Vol XVIII No 3, November 1962 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - The Quarterly Review of Biology March 1964 Vol 39 No1(Unsure of Article) Influence of Day Length in the Chlorophyll content of Wheet Seedlings from (Unknown) (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Organization of Medical Sciences in Costa Rica: Problems of an Underdeveloped Area from The Graduate Center for Latin American Studies, Vanderbilt University, Occasional Papers (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Photosynthesis of Certain Soybean Mutants from Bul Torrey Botanical Club Vol 92 No 2, March 1965 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - The Effects of Amitrole upon Nucleic Acid and Protein Metabolism of Wheat Seedlings from Physiologia Plantarum Vol 18, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Effect of Amitrole in Ultrastructure of Plastids in Seedlings from Plant and Cell Physiol., 6, (1965) (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - An Analysis of the Free Sugars of Ferns by Gas-Liquid Chromatography from Phytochemistry Vol 5, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - The Effects of some Synthetic Quinones on the Hill Reaction in Spinach Chloroplasts from Phytochemisrty Vol 5, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - The Fatty Acids of Chloroplasts from Unknown (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Anthocyanin Pigment Formation in Wheat Seedlings Following Treatment with Amitrole from Biochimica et Biophysica Acta 136, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Exogenous Precursors of Starch Synthesis in the Leaves of Wheat Seedlings from Zeitschrift Fur Pflanzenphysiologie Band 57, Heft 2, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - The Fluorescence of Carotenoids from Photochemisrty and Photobiology Vol 6 1967 Psoralen in the Seeds of Psoralea Psoralioides (Leguminosae) from Unknown Psoralen, an Inhibitor in the Seeds of Psoralea Subacaulis (Leguminosae) from Phytochemistry Vol 6 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Enzymatic Activities in the Leaves of Light-grown and Dark-grown Wheat Seedlings from Zeitschrift Fur Pflanzenphysiologie Band 59, Heft 1, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Carbon Dioxide Production Accompanying Development of Fruiting Bodies of Agaricus Campestris from Separatum Vol 35 No 2, Jul 1968 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Fluorescence Spectra of Some Hydroxy-Cinnamic Acid Derivatives from Advancing Frontiers of Plant Sciences Vol 21 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Photosynthetic and Respiratory Rates as Influenced by Temperature and Light Intensity from Journal of Tennessee Academy of Science Vol 44, No 1, January 1969 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - The Anthocyanin of the Autumn Leaves of Japanese Barberry from Bul Torrey Botanical Club Vol 96 No 5, September 1969 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - A New Species of Cintractia on Fuirena (Cyperaceae) From Mycologia Vol LXI No 4, July 1969 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Observations on an Outbreak of Pulmonary Aspergillosis from Separatum Vol 38 No 4, October 1969 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Dimorphism in Cladosporium Werneckii from Unknown (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Plants with High Rates of Photosynthesis from The Biologist Vol 51 No 4 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - The Effect of Different Carbon Sources on the Sugar Composition of the Mycelium of Apergillus Niger from Separatum Vol 39 No 3-4, December 1969 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Microbiological Studies of Indonesian Fermented Foodstuffs from Separatum Vol 41 No 3-4, December 1970 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Assorted Articles of Tennessee Fungi (Not written by Fred Wolf) (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Assorted Articles (Not written by Fred Wolf) (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Biology 226 - Taxonomy and Morphology of Non-Vascular Plants and other lectures in a spring binder (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Reprint- Photorespiration, The C-4 Pathway of Photosynthesis and Zrelated Phenomena (Box 6, Folder 105)
  - Reprint - The development of photosynthetic capacity by etiolated seedlings upon illumination (Box 6, Folder 106)
  - Reprint - The growth rate of Polygonum Cuspidatum (Box 6, Folder 107)
  - Reprint - An Unusual Occurrence of Fairy Rings (Box 6, Folder 108)
  - Mimoegraph - Giant Puffball (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Reprint - The Giant Puffball in Tennessee (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Reprint - Effects of Light on the Enzymatic Activities of Green Plants (Box 6, Folder 111)
  - Reprint - Enzymatic Activities as influences by light (Box 6, Folder 112)
  - Reprint - Effect of Various Gas Atmospheres upon the Greening of Etiolated Seedlings (Box 6, Folder 113)
  - Reprint - Dimorphism in a Pathogenic Fusarium (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Reprint - Effects of Coumarin upon Plant Growth and Development (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - Reprint - Photosynthesis and Respiration Rates of Ferns (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - Reprint - The Cultivation of Rust Fungi upon Artificial Media (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - Reprint - Obituary Frederick Adolf Wolf 1885 -1975 (1 of 2)n Mycologia (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - Reprint - Obituary Frederick Adolf Wolf 1885 - 1975 (1 of 2)n Phytopathology (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Photocopy - Obituary Frederick Adolf Wolf 1885-1975 (1 of 2)n ASB Bulletin (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Effects of Phenolic Acids and their Derivatives upon the Growth of Avena Coleoptiles (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - Reprint - Enzymes of Dictyuchus Monosporus (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Reprint - Aquatic Phycomycetes of Radnor Lake, Nashville, Tennessee (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Reprint - Effects of Some Phenolic Acids upon the Germination of Lettuce Seed (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Reprint - Proteins in Relation to Growth of Avena Coleoptile Segments (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - Reprint - Effects of Chemical agents in Inhibition og Chlorophyll synthesis and Chloroplast development in Higher Plants (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - Reprint - Effects of Light Quality upon the growth of Avena Coleoptiles (Box 6, Folder 127)
  - Reprint - Kudzu(Pueraria Lobata): Potential Agricultural and Industrial Resource (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - Reprint - Sporulation and Zonation in Stemphylium (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - Reprint - Studies of Aquatic Fungi, especially Blastocladiales and Saprolegniales (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Reprint - The Biology of Entomophthora (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Reprint - Lipid Composition and Metabolism in Oospores and Oospheres of Achlya americana (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - Reprint - Stimulatory and Inhibitory effects of light upon Auxin Biosynthesis (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Reprint - Injury to Automobile paint by Sphaerobolus (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - Entomophthorales and their parasitism of insects (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - Materials from the International Congress for Microbiology, Mexico 1970 (Box 6)
  - Bound - Research Reprints, 1933-1951 (Box 6)
  - Bound - Research Reprints, 1952-1968 (Box 6)
  - Botany 248 Methods in Plant Physiology Laboratory (Box 6)
  - Plant Physiology 146 Laboratory (Box 6)
  - Laboratory Notebooks (Physiology B) From Harvard (Taken from a three ring binder) (Box 6)
  - Laboratory Notebooks From Harvard (Taken from a three ring binder) (Box 6)
- Subject Files (Mostly Academic Materials)
  - Botany 107 Lecture Notes - Morphology of Gymnosperms (Box 7)
  - Botany 113 Pteridophytes Lectures (Box 7)
  - Botany 113 Pteridophytes Laboratory (Box 7)
  - Plant Physiology 146 Reading (Box 7)
  - Botany 248 Methods in Plant Physiology Lectures (Box 7)
  - Seminar Outlines, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - Biology 223 Taxonomy of Vascular Plants - Part I Pteridophytes - Lecture Notes - VU Fall, 1939-1940 (Box 7)
  - Botany 107 Morphology of Gymnosperms Laboratory Botany Laboratory Morphology of Bryophytes (Box 7)
  - Biological Laboratories Harvard University 1939 -Dept. of Biology Vanderbilt University -Basidiomycetes Paleobotany (Box 7)
  - Biology 16b - Mycology - Dr. Sinder (Box 7)
  - Life History and Development of Some Fungi - Fred Wolfe - June 1911, Cornell Univ. Thesis for PhD Book - bound articles by Fred Wolf Master Thesis (Box 7)
  - Reprints - Some Observations Concerning Applied Microbiology in the People Republic of China Gordon Research Conference Plymouth, N.H., 1969 (Box 7)
  - International Minerals and Chemical Corp. Symposium, Chicago, Oct.5-7, 1966 (Box 7)
  - International Minerals and Chemical Corp. Symposium, Chicago, Oct.5-7, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Photos, Negatives, Drawing, Etc. (Box 7)
  - Photos, Negatives, Drawings, Etc. (Box 7)
  - Slides for ASB - Dept. of Illustration No A-751 (Box 7)
  - Allomyces - Miscellaneous Drawings, Negatives. Etc. (Box 7)
- Subject Files (Mostly Travel Files)
  - Card File - Citation for articles and reviews written by Frederick T. Wolf (Box 8)
  - NATO Conference - Aberystwyth, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Gordon Conference, June 30 - July 4, 1969 (Box 8)
  - VI International Congress on Photobiology - Bochum, Germany, Aug 20-25, 1972 (Box 8)
  - IX International Congress for Microbiology - Moscow, U.S.S.R., July 24-30, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Fifth International Photobiology Congress, Aug 26-31, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Fifth International Photobiology Congress, Aug 26-31, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Conference on Photosynthetic Pigments - Argonne National Laboratory, Nov 7-8, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Second International Conference on Opportunistic Fungal Infections - Lexington, KY, Mar 20-22, 1972 (Box 8)
  - International Conference on Photosynthetic Unit - Gatlinburg, Tenn, May 18-21, 1970 (Box 8)
  - X Congreso Internacional de Microbiologia - Mexico City, Aug 9-15, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Eighth International Congress for Microbiology - Montreal, Aug 19-24, 1962 (Box 8)
  - Second International Mycological Congress - Tampa, Florida, Aug 27 - Sept 3, 1977 (Box 8)
  - II Congreso Latinoamericano Y I Nacional de Microbiologia - San Jose, Costa Rica, Dec 10-17, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Fourth International Photobiology Congress - Oxford, England, July 26-30, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Oxford Trip, 1964 (Box 8)
  - First Annual Symposium on Comparative Biology - Asilomar, Pacific Grove, California, Sept 14-17, 1959 (Box 8)
  - Costa Rica, 1965 (Notebook - Diary) (Box 8)
  - Costa Rica, 1965 (Information on The Organization of Tropical Studies) (Box 8)
  - Small Notebook (Diary of Trip ???) (Box 9)
  - Central America July - August 1963 (L.S.U. Interamerican Program-Fellowship) (Box 9)
  - Notebook - Central America, 1963 (Diary) (Box 9)
  - III Congreso Latinoamericano de Microbiologia, (1964) (Box 9)
  - Costa Rica, 1961 (Box 9)
  - VIII International Congress for Microbiology - Montreal, 1962 (Box 9)
  - July - August 1963 Trip (Costa Rica) (Box 9)
  - Wolf, Fred T. (C.V., Lists of Publications, Photos, etc.) (Box 9)
  - Mycology (Myxomycetes and Phycomycetes) (Box 9)
  - Ascomycetes - Fungi Imperfect (Box 9)
  - Basidiomycetes (Box 9)
  - Graduate Students (Mine) (Box 9)
  - S. K. Hasija (Box 9)
  - Nancye Thomas (Box 9)
  - Paul G. Bartels (Box 9)
  - Dwidjoseputro (Box 9)
  - Norman Fox (Box 9)
  - George Kidd (Box 9)